hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the TSA automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
test automation obstacles with Tren tosa
let's look at our next obstacle which is
called the drop-down table okay so in
this particular obstacle we can see
there is a table uh which has got some
text in each arow and also there is a
drop- down with certain values okay now
what we need to do is we need to click
on the generate button and then we need
to select the right values and submit
okay uh we have to note that the drop
down contains only one element matching
the criteria okay so if you have got
something like select word that starts
with letter M then uh we need to select
that particular word which starts with m
which is mobile here then uh it starts
with s uh and this one starts with X
this one starts with v and this one
starts with a okay once we do that we
can click on submit and the obstacle
will be completed so this is a little
bit tricky uh in the sense that you need
to uh know that which letter is being
searched for and then you need to find
out that particular letter and select it
right in the drop down okay so there are
a couple of Concepts uh which you need
to be aware of in order to complete this
particular obstacle so let's see how we
can do this in tosa so coming back to
tosa uh let's go ahead and first scan
this particular
module so here uh we basically need four
different controls uh first two is the
generate and the submit buttons and then
then we require the table which is the
combo box table and we require one of
the select dropdowns now you will notice
that as soon as it's selected tosa will
complain that the selected item is not
unique but I'm not going to make it
unique uh right in this module will
handle it dynamically inside the test
case okay so do not worry about this
particular select drop down right now
just select all of these controls and
then save this particular module and
close it
okay so before designing the test case
now I'm going to first rename this
particular
module okay once that's done then we
come back to our obstacles and then we
create a new test case
here okay and then U I'm going to add
that module but before that let's have a
look at this particular module because
we need to make some changes okay so uh
the links are fine or the buttons
generate and submit are as expected but
here you will notice that when we
scanned all the controls which is the
table and the drop-down they are not in
line with how it looks on the page okay
so here you can see if you consider this
as stable then um the task is one column
the value is another column and then we
have got this cells so this is the first
cell which contains this particular text
and this is the second cell which
contains the drop down right but uh this
is not the way tosa has scanned and
saved this module because the select
drop down is outside the row or the
column right which is not ideal because
we need to make this select drop down as
an embedded control inside one of the
cells okay and to do that what I'm going
to do is I'm going to drag this select
drop down into the particular cell of
that row inside the table okay so I'm
going to drag this and put it inside the
cell so that uh with every row and with
every cell this select drop down will
appear and that is the way I can then
automate this particular problem
okay so now uh we can go ahead and add
this particular module into our test
case so I'm going to drag this and uh
add it to the particular test case here
so now uh the first steps uh it's as I
said it's very simple we just need to
click on these two links so I'm going to
put uh the X here which will do the
click operation and then we will move on
to the next bit which is to adjust the
table okay so here uh what we need to do
is uh we need to select some value in
the drop down but first we need to
buffer this particular letter okay so
once we generate uh this letter will
change so I need to buffer this and put
it into a particular variable now the
normal buffer will not work in this case
because we don't know what this letter
is right and then uh we also don't know
that this is the element which keeps on
changing so in this uh we will try to
use the dynamic X buffer okay so that we
can verify and we can also buffer this
particular text at the same time okay so
here coming to row okay I know that it
will be the second row because the first
row is the row header and we'll start
with the second row here okay so I'm
going to specifically mention that it
selects the second row for me okay and
then moving on uh I want to select the
first cell which contains the text okay
and here uh I'm going to use the X
buffer but for that I need the partial
text which remains constant and then the
dynamic part of it I will buffer which
is this particular letter okay so here
I'm going to type this text and then I'm
going to use the buffer here which is
the dynamic buffer so it is called the
XB and inside this I'm going to write
the buffer name which will store it uh
which I'll call it
letter okay so the action mode will
remain as verify
here uh but it will not only verify this
text it will also buffer this particular
letter okay so coming to the next cell
which contains the drop down okay so I
will select the next cell here uh by by
default it will change it to verify but
make sure you uh change it to select so
that it selects the second cell and then
it goes into the drop-down here I'm
going to call the buffer which I have
stored earlier so I will call B of
letter and also we need to use some
regular expression here so that the
remaining part of the text can be
selected automatically
okay so this is what uh we have to do
for all the different rows okay so there
are 1 2 3 four more rows and we need to
perform the same operation again okay so
here again uh this will be the third
row and then um it will be the same
so we will do
one
and we copy this
okay and then in the second
cell we will select and we will enter
the same
buffer okay so we can use the same
buffer every time it doesn't matter
because it will overwrite the previous
value okay so you don't need to use new
buffers all the
time uh but let's go ahead and also use
this select
okay so let's try and actually try to
copy this and see if we are able to
waste it so that I don't need to rewrite
this again and
again okay so this will do and then I'm
going to just do it three more times
okay and then I'm just going to change
the row number
here and and the remaining part of it
will still remain the same okay so we
have got in total five rows and that's
what we have got in this particular
application
okay so this should work uh but let's go
ahead and see whether it is working or
not so I'm going to mark it as completed
and I'm going to try and run this now
okay uh but first let me take this page
to the initial
uh page
okay and then I'm going to run this
particular test
case Okay so as you can see in the
background uh it has selected all the
different letters uh which start with
that particular character in the
drop-down and it was able to complete
this obstacle
successfully okay so this is how you can
use the dynamic X buffer to buffer some
Dynamic text from your application and
then you can use some regular expression
to choose any particular text which is
dynamic in nature from the drop-down
without even knowing what that
particular element is inside the
dropdown that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video